Guide to the Records of Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137 WAG.180
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137 Records
1916-1997, 2007, 2019-ongoing
1968-1993
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Sheet Metal Workers' International Association. Local 137
WAG.180
12.5 Linear Feet in 10 record cartons, 2 manuscript boxes, one flat box, one folder, and one oversize folder.
2 websites in two archived websites.
Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137 is the Greater New York, Long Island, Westchester and Rockland local union of the International Association of Sheet Metal, Air, Rail, and Transportation Workers. Most of its members' work is fabricating, rigging, and installing metal signboards. This has included production of many of the electric signs on Broadway's "Great White Way," the time ball used at New Year's Eve celebrations at Times Square, as well as signs for suburban shopping centers. Its charter was issued in 1924, but the Local was founded earlier, possibly as early as 1911. The collection includes correspondence, executive board minutes, apprenticeship records, contracts, and a small number of photographs, mainly from the 1970s and 1980s. This collection also includes an archived version of Local 137's website, http://www.local137.com. An early version of the website was first captured in September 2007, although regular web crawls began in June 2019 of their new web address, http://www.smart137.com.
Scope and Contents
The records include correspondence, executive board minutes, apprenticeship records, contracts, and a small number of photographs, mainly from the 1970s and 1980s. Local 137's websites, http://www.local137.com and http://www.smart137.com, contain event listings, a blog, images from events, and information on their apprenticeship program. An early version of the website was first captured in September 2007, and regular web crawls began in June 2019.
Related Archival Materials
Morris Rosen Papers (TAM 078)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137, in February 2000. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2000.014 and 2000.015.
http://www.local137.com was initially selected by curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2007 as part of the Labor Unions and Organizations Web Archive. In 2014, the archived website was added to the collection finding aid. When preparing the collection for offsite storage in 2019, it was found that there was only one 2007 capture of the archived website. In 2015, the website was selected to be migrated to Archive-It but the majority of the crawls were lost during the migration process. In 2019, crawls were resumed using the local's current URL, http://www.smart137.com/. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. The accession number associated with this website is 2019.141.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical Note
Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137 is the Greater New York, Long Island, Westchester and Rockland local union of the International Association of Sheet Metal, Air, Rail, and Transportation Workers. Its charter was issued in 1924, as part of what was then the Amalgamated Sheet Metal Workers' International Alliance, but the Local was founded earlier, possibly as early as 1911. Local 137 originally organized workers doing custom automobile body work, but most of its members soon shifted to the skilled work of fabricating and erecting metal signboards (although portion also have worked in production shops making stove tops, electric metal components, and lockers). In collaboration with members of New York City area electricians' and painters' union locals, Local 137 employees fabricated many of the electric and neon signs on Broadway' "Great White Way," and as well as (as employees of ArtKraft Strauss, one of the premiere sign-making companies in the United States) the time ball that has descended each year at the New Year's Eve celebration on Times Square). Local 137 members have also produced signs, billboards, and banners for well-known New York City locations such as Yankee Stadium and Kennedy Airport, and worked on the restoration of several New York City landmarks, including the Apollo Theater and Nathan's Famous Hotdogs. Members have also worked in the New York City metropolitan area, as far afield as New Jersey. The collapse in 1970 of the Broadway Central Hotel, in which the Local's offices were located, destroyed some of its earliest records. The Local purchased its own building in Woodside, Queens, in 1983.
Local 137 members are required to complete a five-year apprenticeship training program that offered by the Local.
Presidents of the Local have included Moe Rosen, Bernard Friedlander, Martin Fruchter, William Fotiadis, and Paul Collins, Jr.
Arrangement
Contents of collection has been arranged by archivist in boxes by topic.
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Bibliographical Note
Information for this guide was drawn from "Ordinary People, Extraordinary Lives--Labor History in New York City," by Janet Wells Greene, from the March 2000 issue of Annotation (newsletter of the National Historical Publications and Records Commission); "The Sign Industry of New York City," senior thesis by Bernard Friedlander, Empire State Labor College, New York, undated; "Sheet Metal Workers Local 137--A Century of Sign Making," Louis M. Brill, SignWeb (online companion to Signs of the Times), posted June 7, 2010; The Sheet Metal Workers' Story: A Chronicle of Fine Craftsmanship 1888 - 1980, Arch A. Mercey, Merkle Press, Glen Dale, Maryland, 1980; "Sheet Metal Workers' International Association Local # 137," Claudia Hommel, New York City Labor Records Survey (LRS#292), 1985.
Metal-workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Black-and-white photographs.; Collective bargaining -- Metal-workers; Collective labor agreements -- New York (State) -- New York; Fruchter, Martin; Fotiadis, William; Rosen, Morris, 1896-1962; Collins, Paul, Jr.; ArtKraft Strauss; Friedlander, Bernard; Sheet Metal Workers' International Association. Local 137
- Executive board minutes and general meeting minutes; Strike vote, election ballots, and voting roster; Correspondence and general files; Attendance cards and membership dues; Apprenticeship program draft, 1956-1990 (Box 1)
- Correspondence and contracts; Campaign literature (William Fotiadis); Testimonial dinner program (Moe Rosen); Legal files; Photographs; Newspaper clippings, 1948-1996 (Box 2)
- Correspondence, contracts, and monthly reports, 1968-1991 (Box 3)
- Apprenticeship and attendance records; Correspondence and contracts; Events materials; Legal files; Union label reports; General files, 1968-1996 (Box 4)
- General correspondence and contracts, 1966-1992 (Box 5)
- New Jersey Local 172, 1975-1990 (Box 6)
- Tenney Engineering, Local 28, 1972-1993 (Box 7)
- Apprenticeship program and job training materials; Correspondence and general files; Contracts and negotiations, 1988-1995 (Box 8)
- Correspondence and contracts; Pension report; Visit records, 1984-1993 (Box 9)
- Correspondence and contracts; Moe Rosen photographs (circa 1951-1985) and events ledger (1973-1977), 1951-1997 (Box 10)
- Button collection (William Fotiadis); Union label stickers, circa 1970-1996 (Box 11)
- Executive board minutes and general meeting minutes (originals), 1956-1986 (Box 12, Box 13)
- Certificate of Incorporation for Sheet Metal Workers Sick and Benevolent Association of New York, from State of New York, 1916 (Box MSOS003, Folder 1)
- Photographs, circa 1930s-1950s (Box A005, Folder 1)
  Scope and Content Note
  Five black and white photographs, including an undated group portrait shot outside "the Marble Shop" in the Bronx, group shots of Local 137 members on the job, at a demonstration, and at a conference.
- Archived Websites, September 2007, June 2019-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
  Scope and Contents
  The mission of the Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local Union No. 137 is to organize, educate, and represent all workers in associated crafts in the New York region. The purpose of the Union is to represent all members in their fight to improve benefits, wages, and safe working conditions. The website contains event listings, a blog, images from events, and information on their apprenticeship program. In 2014, the Sheet Metal Workers International Association officially merged with United Transportation Union.
  Accruals
  Since June 2019, new site crawls of smart137.com are accrued semi-annually.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.